Arise for Social Justice Records, 1956-2010 (bulk 1985-2010)
Sophia Smith Collection
- SERIES XII. HOUSING, [see also SERIES II. FINANCIAL MATERIALS, SERIES XI. HOMELESSNESS, and SERIES XVIII. POVERTY/ECONOMIC JUSTICE]
  - Single Room Occupancy Residences (SRO)
    - Springfield
      - Rainville Hotel, 32 Byers St.
        - Tenants 1994-97, undated (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Springfield, Massachusetts and region
    - General 1980-98, undated (Box 19, Folder 8-11)
    - Affordable housing development 1985-91 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Coalition of Springfield Housing Nonprofits 1988-89 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Housing Allowance Project/Hamden Hampshire Housing Partnership (HAP, Inc.) 1985-97, undated (Box 19, Folder 14-15)
    - McKnight Community Residential Program 1988-89, undated (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - Metro Center Community Development Corporation 1988-90, undated (Box 19, Folder 17)
    - Springfield City-Wide Tenants Meeting 1988, undated (Box 19, Folder 18)
    - Springfield Community Land Trust 1988-92, undated (Box 19, Folder 19)
    - West Springfield Urban Development Action Grant 1989 (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Springfield, City of
    - General 1982-91, undated (Box 19, Folder 21)
    - Community Development Block Grant Performance Audit Review 1987 (Box 19, Folder 22)
    - Comprehensive Housing Affordability Strategy (CHAS)
      - General 1990-91 (Box 19, Folder 23)
      - Preliminary plan Aug 1991 (Box 19, Folder 24)
      - Final plan Oct 1991 (Box 19, Folder 25)
      - Draft Annual 1993 Plan and 1992 Performance Report1992-93 (Box 19, Folder 26)
    - Mayor's Housing Task Force 1988
      - General (Box 19, Folder 27)
      - Minutes (Box 19, Folder 28)
      - Report (Box 19, Folder 29)
    - "Springfield Housing Opportunity," 1989 (Box 19, Folder 30)
    - Springfield Redevelopment Authority (SRA) 1990, undated (Box 19, Folder 31)
  - Tenant organizations
    - General 1985-89, undated (Box 19, Folder 32)
    - Tenant Organizations in Public Housing 1971-83, undated (Box 19, Folder 33)
    - Allen Park Apartments Tenants Association, Springfield 1988-90 (Box 19, Folder 34)
    - Indian Motorcycle Tenants Council, Springfield 1989, undated (Box 19, Folder 35)
    - Marble Street Apartments Tenants Advisory Council, Springfield 1984-88 (Box 19, Folder 36)
    - Massachusetts Tenants Organization (MTO)
      - General 1988-90, undated (Box 19, Folder 37)
      - Clippings and press releases 1987-91, undated (Box 19, Folder 38)
      - Correspondence 1986-91, undated (Box 19, Folder 39)
      - Fundraising 1991, undated (Box 19, Folder 40)
      - Log book 1988-90, undated (Box 19, Folder 41-46)
      - Meeting and Organizing Summary forms 1990 (Box 19, Folder 47)
      - Omni Group bankruptcy 1989, undated (Box 19, Folder 48)
      - Publications and Fact Sheets 1985-89, undated (Box 19, Folder 49)
      - South Summer Street, Holyoke 1990, undated (Box 19, Folder 50)
    - Pine James Tenants Council, Springfield undated (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Security Manor Apartments and Van Deene Manor Tenants Associations, Westfield and West Springfield 1989 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Sullivan Tenant Council, Springfield 1987-2000, undated (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Whiting Farms/Holyoke Hills Tenant Council, Holyoke 1989-91, undated (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Transitional Housing for Single Parent Families Project (Arise) 1986-88, undated (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Voucher Programs (U.S. Section 8 and Massachusetts Chapter 707 and 726 certificates) 1986-98, undated (Box 20, Folder 6-8)
  - Western Massachusetts Legal Services 1987-95, undated (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Subject files
    - AIDS housing 1993 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Code enforcement 1988, undated (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Co-housing 1989, undated (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Community Development Corporations 1989, undated (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - Community Land Trusts 1982-88, undated (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Discrimination in housing/"Fair housing," 1986-98, undated (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - Elderly housing 1985-89, undated (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - Eviction 1986-89, undated (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - Fair market rents 1980-83, undated (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - Funding alternatives 1988-93, undated (Box 20, Folder 19)
    - Handicapped 1991 (Box 20, Folder 20)
    - Homesteading undated (Box 20, Folder 21)
    - Inclusionary zoning/"Linkage," 1981-87, undated (Box 20, Folder 22)
    - Lead poisoning 1988-93 (Box 20, Folder 23)
    - Limited Equity Cooperatives 1990-95 (Box 20, Folder 24)
    - Local housing partnerships 1988-90 (Box 20, Folder 25)
    - Mobile homes and mobile home parks 1986-90, undated (Box 20, Folder 26)
    - Rent strikes 1986, undated (Box 20, Folder 27)
    - Tenant screening 1985-88, undated (Box 20, Folder 28)
    - Tenants' rights
      - General 1986-89, undated (Box 20, Folder 29)
      - "Public and Subsidized Housing: An Overview of Tenants' Rights" by Mac McCreight 1986 (Box 20, Folder 30)
    - Reference file
      - Fact sheets undated (Box 20, Folder 31)
      - General 1980-90, undated (Box 20, Folder 32)
- SERIES XIII. IMMIGRANTS AND REFUGEES
  - General 1985-2003, undated (Box 20, Folder 33)
  - Friends of Immigrants Network 1996, undated (Box 20, Folder 34)
  - Massachusetts Immigrant and Refugee Advocacy Coalition (MIRA) 1995-98, undated (Box 20, Folder 35)
  - National Network for Immigrant and Refugee Rights 1993-96 (Box 20, Folder 36)
  - Proposition 187 1995, undated (Box 20, Folder 37)
  - Welfare reform and immigrants
    - General 1996-98 (Box 20, Folder 38)
    - Massachusetts Law Reform Institute Basic Benefits Training 22 Jan 1997 (Box 20, Folder 39)
- SERIES XIV. JOBS AND LABOR, [see also SERIES XI. HOMELESSNESS, SERIES XV. PEACE, SERIES XVIII. POVERTY/ECONOMIC JUSTICE, SERIES XX. SOLIDARITY, and SERIES XXIV. WELFARE]
  - General 1988-98, undated (Box 20, Folder 40)
  - Arise
    - Job Bank 1990-96, undated (Box 20, Folder 41)
    - Jobs and Skills Committee 1992 (Box 20, Folder 42)
  - Farm workers 1983-91, undated (Box 20, Folder 43)
  - Jobs With Justice 1987-98, undated (Box 20, Folder 44-45)
  - Massachusetts Campaign for Jobs and Justice 1989 (Box 20, Folder 46)
  - Mine workers 1989, undated (Box 20, Folder 47)
  - Minimum wage 1987-89, undated (Box 20, Folder 48)
  - National Jobs for All Coalition 1998, undated (Box 20, Folder 49)
  - Pioneer Valley Central Labor Council, AFL-CIO 1992-98, undated (Box 20, Folder 50)
  - Sexual harassment 1993-97, undated (Box 20, Folder 51)
  - Unemployment and Workers' Compensation 1991, undated (Box 20, Folder 52)
  - Western Massachusetts Coalition for Occupational Safety and Health (Western MassCOSH) 1993, 1998, undated (Box 20, Folder 53)
  - Western Massachusetts Labor Action 1988, undated (Box 20, Folder 54)
  - Working Massachusetts 1997-99, undated (Box 20, Folder 55-57)
- SERIES XV. PEACE, [see also SERIES XVIII. POVERTY/ECONOMIC JUSTICE, SERIES XX. SOLIDARITY, and SERIES XXIII. VIOLENCE]
  - General 1986-2004, undated (Box 21, Folder 1-3)
  - Arise Peace Committee/Peace With Justice Committee 2002-05, undated (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Gulf War 1990-91, undated (Box 21, Folder 5-6)
  - Jobs With Peace Campaign, "Homes Not Bombs," 1988-90, undated (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Military/defense spending 1982-2005, undated (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Military recruiting in schools 1991, undated (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - National Coalition to Stop U.S. Intervention in the Middle East 1991, undated (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Sedition Committee 1988-89, undated (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Springfield Anti-war Coalition 1990-91, undated (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - War tax resisters (Kehler and Corner) 1992 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Reference file 1990-2005 (Box 21, Folder 14)
- SERIES XVI. PEER SUPPORT
  - General 1986, undated (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Advocacy, [see also Restricted materials]
    - General 1986-91, undated (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - Educator/Advocate's report to Arise Board 1993 (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - Referral lists 1991-92 (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - Training 1989-93, undated (Box 21, Folder 19)
    - Springfield Citizen Advocacy Project 1985, undated (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - Disability
    - General 1990-96, undated (Box 21, Folder 21)
    - Social Security 1990-93 (Box 21, Folder 22)
  - Gay, Lesbian, Bisexual, and Transgender (GLBT) 1993-2000 (Box 21, Folder 23)
  - Moms in Stress Support Group 1986, undated (Box 21, Folder 24)
  - Self-Reliance Center/Self-Reliance Project
    - General 1992-94, undated (Box 21, Folder 25-27)
    - Budget and grants 1994, undated (Box 21, Folder 28)
    - Worthington St. lease 1993 (Box 21, Folder 29)
    - Local Currency/Ithaca Hours 1933, 1991-94, undated (Box 21, Folder 30)
    - Notes 1994, undated (Box 21, Folder 31)
    - SHARE (Self-Help and Resource Exchange) 1988-93, undated (Box 21, Folder 32)
    - Skills Exchange 1989-95, undated (Box 21, Folder 33)
    - Tool Lending Library 1978-93, undated (Box 21, Folder 34)
  - Veterans
    - Advocacy 1986-92, undated (Box 21, Folder 35)
    - Reference file 1978-97, undated (Box 21, Folder 36)
- SERIES XVII. POLITICAL PARTICIPATION
  - General and miscellaneous 1985-2005, undated (Box 21, Folder 37)
  - Arise Electoral Committee 2003 (Box 21, Folder 38)
  - Ballot initiatives
    - General 1987-2004, undated (Box 21, Folder 39)
    - Question 3 sponsored by Citizens for Limited Taxation 1990 (Box 21, Folder 40)
  - Campaign finance reform/clean elections 1988-97, undated (Box 21, Folder 41)
  - Conference "Private Money in Public Elections, Electoral and Legislative Consequences," Center for Responsive Politics 1991 (Box 21, Folder 42)
  - Democratic Party platform 1985 (Box 21, Folder 43)
  - Legislator contact information 1993-98, undated (Box 21, Folder 44)
  - New Alliance Party/Lenora Fulani 1987-88 (Box 21, Folder 45)
  - New Party 1993 (Box 21, Folder 46)
  - Jesse Jackson for President/Rainbow Coalition 1987-88 (Box 21, Folder 47)
  - Neighbor to Neighbor 1997-99, [see also Voter registration below] (Box 21, Folder 48)
  - Pioneer Valley Pro-Democracy Campaign 1990-92, undated (Box 21, Folder 49)
  - Voter registration
    - General 1987-99, undated (Box 21, Folder 50)
    - Arise campaigns
      - 1985-92 (Box 21, Folder 51-57)
      - 1993-97 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Organizers' Training Project/Voter Registration and Mobilization 1999 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Voter Reg-a-thon 1999 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Voter Mobilization, "Turn up the heat, get out the vote campaign," 1997-2003 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Women's Statewide Legislative Network 1986-94, undated (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Springfield, Massachusetts, Ward Representation/Campaign for Fair Politics
    - General 1993-2004, undated (Box 22, Folder 6-11)
    - Flyers and handouts 1993-2004, undated (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Press releases and clippings 1956, 1997-2004 (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Voting Rights Conference 1993 (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Voter information (Box 22)
- SERIES XVIII. POVERTY/ECONOMIC JUSTICE, [see also SERIES XI. HOMELESSNESS, SERIES XII. HOUSING, SERIES XV. PEACE, and SERIES XXIV. WELFARE]
  - Arise
    - General 1997, 2005, undated (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Arise Anti-Poverty [Issues] Committee 1996-99, undated (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - Arise Economic Justice Committee 2003-06, undated (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - Speakers Bureau
      - General 1985-2005, undated (Box 22, Folder 18-20)
      - Western New England College Social Work Conference 1988 (Box 22, Folder 21)
      - Bertha Capen Reynolds Society Annual Conference 1997-98 (Box 22, Folder 22)
      - The Fight for Abortion Rights and Reproductive Freedom 1993 (Box 22, Folder 23)
      - Notes and texts undated (Box 22, Folder 24)
    - Truth Squad Project 1999-2000, undated (Box 22, Folder 25)
  - Conferences/summits
    - "The War on Poverty Revisited: Strategies for the 90s," 1988 (Box 22, Folder 26)
    - First National Survival Summit, Philadelphia 21-23 Jul 1989 (Box 22, Folder 27)
    - Poverty: How it Affects Your Community, co-sponsored by Arise 16-18 Aug 1989 (Box 22, Folder 28)
    - Up and Out of Poverty Now Southern Summit 20-22 Jul 1990 (Box 22, Folder 29)
    - New England People's Economic Summit, United for Social Justice Project (cancelled)
      - General and miscellaneous 1995-96, undated (Box 22, Folder 30)
      - Correspondence 1995-96, undated (Box 22, Folder 31)
      - Committees 1995-97, undated (Box 22, Folder 32-33)
      - Southern Regional Team/Outreach Committee
        - General 1996, undated (Box 22, Folder 34)
        - Minutes 1996 (Box 22, Folder 35)
        - Hiring process for organizers 1996 (Box 22, Folder 36)
      - Planning and logistics 1995-96 (Box 22, Folder 37)
      - Financial 1995-96 (Box 22, Folder 38)
      - Interested organizations list undated (Box 22, Folder 39)
      - Survey undated (Box 22, Folder 40)
      - Mailing list undated (Box 22, Folder 41)
    - Poor People's Summit, Philadelphia 9-11 Oct 1998 (Box 22, Folder 42)
    - Towards a Fair Economy 1999 (Box 22, Folder 43)
  - Projects, programs, and campaigns
    - General 1987, 1991 (Box 22, Folder 44)
    - Economic Human Rights Campaign, Kensington Welfare Rights Union
      - General 1997-2004 (Box 22, Folder 45)
      - Freedom Bus 1998 (Box 22, Folder 46)
      - National Planning Meeting 4 Dec 1998 (Box 22, Folder 47)
      - Bus trip to United Nations 1999 (Box 22, Folder 48)
      - Economic Human Rights Violation Report forms 1998-99, undated (Box 22, Folder 49-50)
    - Financial Democracy Campaign 1990-91, undated (Box 22, Folder 51)
    - Fuel Assistance 1984-95, undated (Box 22, Folder 52)
    - National People's Campaign 1993, undated (Box 22, Folder 53)
    - National Priorities Project (Box 23, Folder 1-2)
    - Petition for New Priorities circa 1996 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Share the Wealth Project 1993-95, undated (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Taxes
      - General 1988-95, undated (Box 23, Folder 5)
      - Anti-Citizens for Limited Taxation Ballot Question 3 fall 1990 (Box 23)
        - General 1990 (Box 23, Folder 6)
        - Campaign for Massachusetts' Future 1990 (Box 23, Folder 7)
        - Massachusetts Human Services Coalition 1990 (Box 23, Folder 8)
        - Massachusetts Law Reform Institute 1990 (Box 23, Folder 9)
      - Tax Equity Alliance for Massachusetts (TEAM) 1989-99, undated (Box 23, Folder 10-11)
    - Unite for Social Justice Project: Directory of Low-Income, Membership-Based Social Justice Organizations
      - General undated (Box 23, Folder 12)
      - Maine organizations 1996, undated (Box 23, Folder 13)
      - Massachusetts organizations 1996, undated (Box 23, Folder 14)
      - Vermont organizations 1995-96, undated (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - "Up to Poverty" (Massachusetts) and "Up and Out of Poverty Now" (national)
      - General 1985-94, undated (Box 23, Folder 16-25)
      - Women for Economic Justice 1984-85, undated (Box 23, Folder 26)
      - Women's Campaign for Social Justice 1985-88, undated (Box 23, Folder 27-29)
    - Utilities campaigns
      - General 1993-2005, undated (Box 23, Folder 30)
      - Western Massachusetts Electric Company rate revolt 1977-88, undated (Box 23, Folder 31-32)
      - Utility shut-offs 1993 (Box 23, Folder 33)
  - Organizations
    - General 1987-2004, undated (Box 23, Folder 34)
    - Center on Budget and Policy Priorities 1995, undated (Box 23, Folder 35)
    - Committee on Economic Insecurity 1996, undated (Box 23, Folder 36)
    - Community Reinvestment Coalition 1992-93, undated (Box 23, Folder 37)
    - Economic Survival Coalition 1997-99, undated (Box 23, Folder 38)
    - Empowerment Planning Group 1994 (Box 23, Folder 39)
    - Haymarket People's Fund: Western Massachusetts Board (Marsha Burnett) 1993-94 (Box 23, Folder 40)
    - Institute for Community Economics 1984-93 (Box 23, Folder 41)
    - Low Income Students for Survival (LISS) 1987 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Maine Economic Conversion Project 1993-94 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - National Council of La Raza Poverty Project Newsletter (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - National Impact 1988-90, undated (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Piedmont Peace Project 1994 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Poverty and Race Research Action Council 1992-97 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Western Massachusetts Community Loan Fund: Board of Directors 1988-89 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Reference materials
    - General 1983-2004, undated (Box 24, Folder 8-11)
    - "Running in Place: A Report on Poverty in Massachusetts," Massachusetts Community Action Program Nov 1997 (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - "The War Against the Poor: A Defense Manual" undated (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - "Women in Community Service (WICS) Alexandria, Virginia: Developmental Evaluation Interim Report No. 2" Sep 1996 (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - Banking
      - General 1986-92, undated (Box 24, Folder 15)
      - Community Reinvestment Act 1989-90 (Box 24, Folder 16)
      - "Halting Displacement and Neighborhood Blight Through Lender Liability" by Erin Kemple circa 1992 (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - Budget, Massachusetts
      - General 1986-95, undated (Box 24, Folder 18)
      - Poor People's Budget, FY 86, FY 89, FY 91, 1985-95, undated (Box 24, Folder 19-21)
    - Budget, U.S. 1983-96, undated (Box 24, Folder 22)
    - Community development/healthy communities
      - General 1986-88, undated (Box 24, Folder 23)
      - Community Empowerment Act 1995, undated (Box 24, Folder 24)
      - Lower Pioneer Valley Healthy Communities Dialogues 1996-2002 (Box 24, Folder 25)
    - Corporations 1993-98 (Box 24, Folder 26)
    - Economic justice 1987, undated (Box 24, Folder 27)
    - Economic sustainability 1992-94 (Box 24, Folder 28)
    - Energy and the poor 1990 (Box 24, Folder 29)
    - Human rights 1994-98, undated (Box 24, Folder 30)
    - Springfield and New England 1986, undated (Box 24, Folder 30A)
    - Trade 1993, undated (Box 24, Folder 31)
    - Utilities 1985-96, undated (Box 24, Folder 32)
    - Women 1985, undated (Box 24, Folder 33)
- SERIES XVIX. RACISM
  - General 1988-97, undated (Box 24, Folder 34)
  - Arise Board and Committee Diversity Training Jan 1993 (Box 24, Folder 35)
  - Dismantling Racism workshops 1993-94 (Box 24, Folder 36)
  - FORWARD (Fighting Oppression Racism Wrongness Advocating Rights Dignity) 1992, undated (Box 24, Folder 37)
  - Undoing Racism Organizing Committee of Western Massachusetts 1997-2005, undated (Box 24, Folder 38)
  - Reference file 1990-2001, undated (Box 24, Folder 39)
- SERIES XX. SOLIDARITY
  - Arise Solidarity Committee
    - General 1993-96, undated (Box 24, Folder 40)
    - Minutes and agendas 1994-95 (Box 24, Folder 41-43)
    - Campaign for Labor Rights 1992-97, undated (Box 24, Folder 44)
    - Nicaragua delegation (with NECAN)
      - 1994 (Box 24, Folder 45)
      - 1996 (Box 24, Folder 46)
      - Funding proposal 1996, undated (Box 24, Folder 47)
    - Reports 1994-96, undated (Box 24, Folder 48)
  - Organizations
    - American Friends Service Committee 1989-97, undated (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Center for Communication and Popular Education in Nicaragua (CANTERA) 1995 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Central American Solidarity Association (CASA) 1993, undated (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Committee in Solidarity with the People of El Salvador (CISPES) 1996-97, undated (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Network in Solidarity with the People of Nicaragua (NISGUA)
      - General 1994-95, undated (Box 25, Folder 5)
      - Speaking tour 1994-96, undated (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - New England Central America Network (NECAN)
      - General 1994-97, undated (Box 25, Folder 7-8)
      - Fall Conference 1990 (Box 25, Folder 9)
      - Financial 1992-93 (Box 25, Folder 10)
      - Regional Council 1992-94, undated (Box 25, Folder 11)
      - Nicaragua trip Oct 1996 (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Nicaragua Network
      - Education Fund 1993-96 (Box 25, Folder 13)
      - Hotline bulletins 1993-96, undated (Box 25, Folder 14-16)
      - National Leadership Meeting 1997 (Box 25, Folder 17)
    - Springfield Area Central America Project (SECAP)
      - General 1987-93, undated (Box 25, Folder 18)
      - People's Quincentenary Celebration 1992 (Box 25, Folder 19)
    - Western Massachusetts Coalition Against Apartheid (Box 25, Folder 20)
  - Reference files
    - General 1988-2003, undated (Box 25, Folder 21-22)
    - Africa 1987-91, undated (Box 25, Folder 23)
    - Central America and Solidarity movement 1992-94, undated (Box 25, Folder 24)
    - Cuba 1989-2002, undated (Box 25, Folder 25)
    - El Salvador 1989-95, undated (Box 25, Folder 26)
    - Guatemala 1992-98, undated (Box 25, Folder 27)
    - Haiti 1994 (Box 25, Folder 28)
    - Labor issues 1993-96, undated (Box 25, Folder 29)
    - Mexico 1994-95, undated (Box 25, Folder 30)
    - Native Americans 1992-97, undated (Box 25, Folder 31)
    - Nicaragua 1990-97 (Box 25, Folder 32)
    - North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA) 1991-92, undated (Box 25, Folder 33)
- SERIES XXI. SPRINGFIELD AND PIONEER VALLEY
  - General 1985-2004, undated (Box 25, Folder 34)
  - Churches
    - General 1985-2000, undated (Box 25, Folder 35)
    - Catholic Diocese of Springfield 1990, undated (Box 25, Folder 36)
  - City Council, Springfield 1991, 2004, undated (Box 25, Folder 37)
  - Neighborhoods
    - General 1989-2000, undated (Box 25, Folder 38)
    - McKnight Neighborhood Council 1988 (Box 25, Folder 39)
    - Upper State Street Community Development Corporation 1985-86 (Box 25, Folder 40)
  - Organizations
    - General 1989-2001, undated (Box 25, Folder 41)
    - Centro Cultural Puertorriqueño, Inc. 1987 (Box 25, Folder 42)
    - Community 2000, 1987-2000 (Box 25, Folder 43)
    - Community Action Program 1985, undated (Box 25, Folder 44)
    - Community Resources Against Community Killers (C.R.A.C.K.) 1986-89, undated (Box 25, Folder 45)
    - Gardening the Community 2004-05, undated (Box 25, Folder 46)
    - Greater Springfield National Organization for Women 1989-95 (Box 25, Folder 47)
    - Hampden County Women's Center 1985-86, undated (Box 25, Folder 48)
    - League of Women Voters of the Springfield Area 1993, 1999, undated (Box 25, Folder 49)
    - Mass Action for Women West 1995-99, undated (Box 25, Folder 50)
    - Open Pantry Community Services 1989-2003, undated (Box 25, Folder 51)
    - Pioneer Valley Project 1994-99, undated (Box 25, Folder 52)
    - Project Self-Sufficiency 1984-86, undated (Box 25, Folder 53)
    - Springfield Action Commission
      - General 1986-90, undated (Box 25, Folder 54)
      - Board of Directors
        - General 1987-98 (Box 25, Folder 55)
        - Low-Income Board Member elections 1993-98 (Box 25, Folder 56)
      - Community Development Block Grant (CDBG) reports 1986-99 (Box 26, Folder 1)
      - Consumer Action Center 1986-88, undated (Box 26, Folder 2)
      - Contracts with Arise 1986-94 (Box 26, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence 1987-99 (Box 26, Folder 4)
      - Financial materials 1986-89 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Springfield Progressives group/alliance 1995 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Springfield Project for a United Neighborhood (SPUN) 1984-87, undated (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Springfield School Committee 1988-97 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - United Way of the Pioneer Valley 1988-93 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Valley Feminist Action Coalition 1995, undated (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Publications, [see also Oversize]
    - Earthline "Building the Movement in Western Mass," 1990-92 (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Murphy Ford's Springfield Gazette 1994 (Box 26, Folder 12)
- SERIES XXII. SUBSTANCE ABUSE
  - General 1985-2003, undated (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Conference: "The War on Substance Abuse-How Does it Affect You and Your Community" Nov 1990 (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Springfield Community Partnership and Prevention Alliance 1992-94, undated (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - Springfield Users' Council 2003-05 (Box 26, Folder 16)